TOKYO DAIICHI BANK NAKANO BRANCH
（东京第一银行 中野分行）
It's unacceptable.
我无法接受
You said you'd leave it up to me.
课长已经把这件事交给我处理
I'm telling you to do things the way they've always been done.
所以照过去的方式处理就行了
Then nothing will ever change!
那事情永远都不会有改变
Banks have customary practices that must be protected.
银行有必须遵循的惯例
With all due respect,
恕我直言
they're not customary practices, just old habits.
那不是惯例 只是陋习
What?
什么？
I think it's important to take on new ideas.
我认为采用新的做法是必须的
However…
但是…
If I cancel now they'll charge me a cancellation fee.
如果现在才取消 会被收取消费用
-So it's okay, right? -What?
-这样没关系吗？ -什么？
And so,
因此 各位
this year's year-end party will be a Christmas party at a fancy restaurant!
年末聚会要在时髦的餐厅 举办圣诞派对！
-Yay! -Wait!
-太棒了！ -等等！
I haven't agreed yet! Stop celebrating!
我还没同意 别高兴得太早！
-Good evening. Wow, how lovely. -What a nice restaurant!
-辛苦了 好可爱！ -这间餐厅真漂亮
Good evening.
辛苦了
This kind of year-end party is always welcome.
最喜欢这样的年末聚会了
-Right? -Good job, Mai.
-就是说啊 -不愧是舞
Having to eat chanko hot pot every year was so depressing.
每年都吃相扑火锅超扫兴的
I'll come here with my fiancé too.
我下次也要带男朋友来
How lucky.
真羡慕
Damn you, Hanasaki.
可恶的花琦
Why do I have to do this?
为什么我得扮成这样？
-Nice work, Soma. -Deputy Manager.
-相马 辛苦了 -次长 辛苦了
Good news. It's not official yet, but you're being sent to headquarters.
恭喜 人事调动确定了 你下个月就去总部
Thank you!
太感谢你了！
Continue to do your best over there.
到那边也要继续努力
-Yes! -Hi, Hanasaki.
-是 -花琦 辛苦了
Good evening.
次长辛苦了
-Nice place. -Thanks.
-真是不错的地方 -谢谢
-Here's your bingo card.
-你的宾果卡
-You can choose your drinks over there. -I'm so excited!
-可以到那边选用饮品 -我好期待
Yes!
太好了！
Hanasaki.
花琦
This is the last time you get to
以后不会再让你
treat me this way!
这样整我了！
TOKYO DAIICHI BANK HEADQUARTERS
（东京第一银行总部）
Did you call me?
您找我吗？
Hey, Soma.
相马 在总部习惯了吗？
for three months by yourself.
真是不好意思
It wasn't so bad once I got used to working by myself.
没关系 我已经习惯一个人处理了
I finally found you a subordinate.
你的部下人选终于确定了
She'll be arriving today.
她今天就会来
I see.
这样啊
Thank you.
谢谢您
I had a hard time selecting someone suitable,
要选出适合人选真不容易
but don't worry. She may be young, but she's an excellent female bank clerk.
你放心 她虽然年轻 却是一位优秀的女职员
-Female bank clerk? -Yeah.
-女职员？ -没错
Our bank needs to create a system that will
我们银行今后也要
be more open to accepting opinions from female employees.
多采纳女性职员的意见
I think that's a great idea.
我认为这样很好
And who is this subordinate…
部长 那位部下是…
She was an excellent bank teller.
她是个优秀的柜员
Bank teller?
柜员？
A teller?
也就是负责柜台事务的人？
-Is something wrong? -No.
-怎么了吗？ -没事
When I was at the branch office,
我在分行的时候
I met a troublesome bank teller.
碰过一个令人头痛的柜员
How so?
怎么说？
To put it nicely, she was a free spirit.
说得好听一点 是个不受拘束的人
She was fearless and once she got riled up,
只要下定决心就勇往直前
even her boss couldn't stop her.
连上司都无法阻止她
She's here. Come in.
她到了 请进吧
Excuse me.
打扰了
Hanasaki!
花琦！
Mr. Soma.
相马前辈
Long time no see.
好久不见
Oh? Do you know each other?
你们两个认识吗？
Yes, we worked together at the Nakano Branch.
是的 我们曾在中野分行共事过
Then we can skip the introductions.
这样啊 那就不用多介绍了
You'll be working together with Ms. Mai Hanasaki.
今后你就跟花琦舞一起工作
Yes, this is Mai Hanasaki.
是 这位就是花琦舞
Thank you very much.
请多多指教
Being transferred to the headquarters was a big surprise.
我得知要被调来总部时吓了一跳
And I get to work with you again.
而且居然再次和相马前辈共事
This is awful.
真倒霉
I guess fate is pulling us together.
我们两个真有缘份呢
Stop being ridiculous.
才不是这样
Good morning.
早安
MANAGING EXECUTIVE OFFICER TSUYOSHI SHINDO
（常务执行董事 真藤毅）
I haven't seen you before.
之前好像没见过你
I've been assigned to the Branch Managing Department.
我是从分行被调过来的 今日到职
My name is Mai Hanasaki.
我叫花琦舞
I see. Having an energetic young lady like yourself will be
原来如此 有你这样 干劲十足的年轻女性加入
a breath of fresh air around here. Good luck.
气氛也变好了呢 好好努力
Thank you very much.
是 谢谢 我会努力的
Who is that?
刚刚那位是？
Mr. Shindo. The Managing Executive and Head of Corporate Planning.
经营企划部部长真藤常务
Candidate for the future president.
是总裁候选人之一
I see.
原来如此
Who was that man?
刚刚那个人是谁？
-Soma from Branch Inspection. -Branch Inspection?
-稽查班的相马 -稽查班？
He's my colleague, but how can I explain it…
我和他是一起入职的 该怎么说呢？
ASSISTANT GM OF CORPORATE PLANNING NAOKI KODAMA
（经营企划部 儿玉直树次长）
-He fell off the fast track. -I see.
-他的升迁之路不顺利 -这样啊
That female employee is a former teller who came in five years ago.
女职员入行五年 之前是柜员
A bank teller, huh.
柜员啊
They're not worth remembering.
他们是不值一提的角色
Yes.
是
It's all men.
同事都是男性啊
By the way, what will I be doing here?
我在这里要做什么呢？
Right here.
就是这里
Branch inspection?
临店稽查？
That's when you visit branches
就是到发生问题的各分行
with problems and give them assistance, right?
稽查并给予指导 是吗？
Yeah. We're the branch inspectors.
对 我们是稽查人员
I get to do such an important job?
我要做这么重要的工作？
Whoa.
天啊
It's just the two of us?
请问只有我们两个人吗？
Is that bad?
怎么了吗？
No, but it seems a little lonely.
没事 只是感觉有点寂寞
That's your desk over there.
你的座位在那里
What…
什么…
-Good morning.
-早安
Oh, you're Hanasaki.
你就是花琦
-Yes. -I'm expecting a lot from you. Good luck.
-是的 -我很看好你 加油
Thank you.
好的
Let's get down to business. Please head to Mukojima Branch.
你们现在就去向岛分行
Will do.
我知道了
-Thanks. -Yes.
-麻烦你们了 -好的
"Lost unused passbooks," huh.
“丢失未使用存折”
Hanasaki.
花琦
-Let me make one thing clear. -What is that?
-我先把话说清楚 -怎么了？
Don't say unnecessary things during the branch inspection.
在分行那边绝对不要多嘴
What?
什么？
Think of it as a different company.
把它当作不同的公司看待
-Okay… -Let's go.
-好 -走吧
What? Wait a minute.
什么？等一下
Oh no!
糟糕
MUKOJIMA BRANCH
（向岛分行）
Therefore, please be careful to prevent such mistakes
今后请小心 不要犯这种错误
in the future.
麻烦大家了
I'll be very careful.
我之后会多加注意
But we're very busy over here.
但我们也很忙碌
Why would you come to give us guidance over some missing passbooks?
为了丢失存折这种小事就叫稽查来
Give me a break.
拜托 饶了我吧！
We'll be off now.
那我们先离开了
This is the job of a branch inspector?
这就是稽查工作吗？
Have some.
吃吧
Our job is to solve and supervise
我们的工作就是到分行
those types of small problems that arise in various branches.
协助解决这类小问题
It's never fun for the branch offices
对分行而言 总部的人
because they feel like they're being nitpicked at by people
就像是特地来挑三拣四的
from headquarters.
一点都不有趣
They hate us.
大家都讨厌我们
Therefore, branch inspection is a job that
所以临店稽查这种事谁都不想做
everyone hates, and no one wants to do.
是大家都讨厌的工作
No way…
怎么这样？
RESTAURANT HANASAKI
（花琦食堂）
I don't believe in fortune-telling anymore.
我不相信占卜了
This year was supposed to be my lucky year,
它说今年是我12年来最好运的一年
but I've only had bad luck.
结果从1月开始就很倒霉
Is that so?
是吗？
Yeah. My favorite plate and mug broke,
对啊 我打破喜欢的盘子和马克杯
my laptop constantly freezes,
电脑一直故障
my lights keep flickering,
房间的灯也一直闪
and when I go to the bathroom, there's no toilet paper.
连上厕所都没卫生纸
This morning I had a run in all of my tights.
今天早上发现没有丝袜穿
You were dumped too.
而且新年还被人甩了
Dad.
爸爸
-Maybe I'll quit. -Stop that.
-还是离职好了 -又来了
When you first started as a teller, all you did was complain.
你刚开始做柜员时也一 直在抱怨
"A client made me cry," "my boss is mean," "I'm going to quit."
客人害我哭了、老板很坏、我要辞职
It was hard, but it was also fun.
那时候虽然辛苦 但是很有趣
And it was a job that made people happy.
是让大家都开心的工作
So I learned to like it over time.
渐渐地我也喜欢上这份工作
But compared to that, a branch inspector
但是比起临店稽查
is like nitpicking errors.
总是在挑别人错误
I wish I could've stayed as a bank teller.
真希望我可以继续当柜员
NEW MESSAGE
（您有一条新消息）
Oh!
啊！
Aki.
是亚纪
Mai, how's the headquarters?
舞 总部的工作如何？
There were lots of clients who were sad to see you gone.
好多客人知道你被调走都很难过
I want to go back.
我好想回去
Oh.
（相马先生来电）
Hello, this is Hanasaki.
喂 我是花琦
Tomorrow is Kayabacho Branch.
明天要去茅场町分行
Okay.
好的
Listen up, Hanasaki. At the branch--
听好了 花琦 在分行那里…
Don't say unnecessary things at the branch office, right?
绝对不要多嘴 对吧？
You were a teller so you may not know
你之前是柜员 可能不晓得
but in the world of banking,
在银行的世界 一旦被踢出去
you can never regain status you've lost.
就不可能再回来了
If you cause any trouble, there will be no future
如果出问题的话 你跟我
for you or me.
明天就都不用来了
I understand.
我了解了
-Your face says otherwise. -No, I understand.
-你的表情看起来不像了解了 -不 我真的了解了
But sometimes, I can't control what comes out of my mouth.
但是我有时候会不小心脱口而出
Let me give you some advice.
我教你一个诀窍
If you have something to say,
想说话的时候 先别说出来
take a deep breath, and swallow it along with those words.
吸一口气 再把想说的话一起吞回去
I feel like I can do it.
我应该做得到
Don't "feel like" you can do it. Just do it.
别说“应该” 做就对了
I'll do my best.
-我会努力的 -总之呢
Smile.
微笑
It's so awkward.
感觉真奇怪
-Don't say-- -Breathe in.
-不要这样说… -吸气
Don't say that…
不要说…
KAYABACHO BRANCH
（茅场町分行）
Our branch does not require any guidance from branch inspectors.
我们分行不需要稽查指导
Right, Deputy General Manager?
对吧 次长？
That's exactly right.
您说得没错
There were five clerical errors last month
上个月发生过五起疏漏
so we're here to inspect the cause.
我们是来调查原因
-And to provide assistance. -That's unnecessary.
-跟提供协助的 -不需如此大费周章
BRANCH MANAGER YAJIMA
（分行行长 矢岛）
It seems like
总部的人看起来
headquarters have a lot of time on their hands.
好像有很多空闲的时间呢
The issues you mentioned have been resolved.
你说的那些事已经解决了
A teller named Satoko Nakajima caused all of those errors,
全部都是一个叫中岛聪子的柜员造成
so we gave her a strict warning.
我们已经严厉告诫过她了
-It was all caused by one person? -Yes.
-全部都是她一个人造成的？ -对
She has 13 years of experience,
她明明有13年的资历
so I don't know how she made those errors.
我也不晓得为什么会犯这种错
It's only a simple teller job.
区区柜员的工作都做不好
-Only? -Smile.
-区区？ -微笑
It's been a year since I came here.
我来这里一年了
We're finally seeing some results,
业绩终于有起色
and it's been boosting the morale of the employees.
职员们的士气也提升了
Yet, all this for one incompetent teller?
却被一个无能柜员犯的错拖累
What a hassle.
真令人困扰
Our Branch Manager is right.
分行长说得没错
There's nothing we require from
我们不需要稽查人员
Branch Inspection.
提供任何协助
May we talk with Ms. Satoko Nakajima
我们可以向中岛聪子
to gather some facts?
询问一下调查所需的信息吗？
I told you,
我已经说了
it's not necessary.
没有这个必要
It's necessary
但是我们
in order for us to submit our report.
还是得写调查报告
Please cooperate with us.
拜托你们了
Please do so without interrupting our business.
那请不要打扰到我们工作
Only a simple teller job? An incompetent teller?
区区一个柜员？无能柜员？
Hanasaki!
花琦！
Don't get riled up!
不要进入暴走模式！
Don't worry.
我没事
Even so, did he have to be
但就算如此
so blatantly rude to us?
也不需要把我们当成敌人吧？
I told you, that's the job of a branch inspector.
我说过了 临店稽查的工作就是这样的
How can you stay so calm?
他那样对人说话
-He can just talk to you like that? -You're just too transparent.
-亏你还能忍受得住 -你的心声都写在脸上了
-Was it that obvious? -Very much so.
-很明显吗？ -非常明显
I didn't notice, since I was too busy trying to stay quiet.
我努力不说话 就忘记脸部表情了
Be careful.
小心一点
You have a scary face.
你的表情很吓人
How mean!
真过分
It seems like that Branch Manager is favored by Mr. Shindo.
那个分行长的靠山应该是真藤部长
-The candidate for the next president? -Yeah. Look at this.
-总裁候选人？ -对 你看
It's almost impossible to raise
只花一年就提升这么多业绩
numbers this much in just one year.
根本是不可能的事
He must be very determined to climb up the promotional ladder.
他非常积极要往上爬
Achievements and results, huh.
大家都把业绩挂在嘴边
Are numbers all that matters?
数字真的有这么重要吗？
That's banks for you.
这就是银行
Stop that scary look.
不要再做吓人的表情了
Ms. Nakajima.
中岛小姐
You seem to be making many clerical errors lately.
你最近好像有不少业务疏漏
How is that possible for someone experienced like yourself?
像你这样资深的柜员
Incorrect account entry, and stamp omission.
记帐疏漏、漏盖印章
All of these are basic tasks.
全都是低级的错误
I'm sorry.
对不起
What do you think is the cause?
原因出在哪里呢？
Ms. Nakajima?
中岛小姐？
I think I became distracted because I let my guard down.
我应该是一时松懈 不够专注
It's all my fault.
全都是我的疏漏
I see.
原来如此
Thank you for your cooperation.
那我们就问到这里
That's it? Weren't you--
就这样？但是…
Please be careful not to make these mistakes again.
之后请小心 不要再犯错
Yes.
是
All right. We found out the cause of the error and gave assistance.
好 我们已经找到原因 也给予指导了
We just have to write our report and we'll be done.
接下来只要把报告写好
What? That's it?
就这样结束了？
We don't really know the cause yet…
我们都还没搞清楚原因
She said herself that she was distracted.
“一时松懈 不够专注”
-That she let her guard down. -You believe that?
-她本人都这样说了 -那只是她的说法
That's usually what causes mistakes.
犯错的原因大多都是这个
But Ms. Nakajima looked like she wanted to say--
但是中岛小姐好像想说什么
You're reading too much into it.
你想太多了吧？
Write the report. I'm off to get coffee.
我去喝咖啡 你去写报告
-Don't snoop around. -I won't.
-不要闲晃 -我知道啦
Sit down.
坐好
Please take a number and wait.
请领取号码 牌稍待
-Please double check. -Sure.
-请再次确认 -嗯
Yes. I'll be right over! Yes.
是 我立刻过去
Here you go.
好了
Mr. Yamada, thank you for waiting.
山田先生 久等了
I'll take your number.
号码牌交给我就可以了
Please confirm this amount.
请确认金额数目
Everyone here is younger than Ms. Nakajima.
中岛小姐的同事都好年轻
I apologize.
非常抱歉
Please take a seat and wait one moment.
请在那边稍后一下
We will call you once it's ready.
准备好后 我们会请您过来
Thank you.
谢谢
Ms. Nakajima.
不好意思 中岛小姐
What should I do with this?
这个要怎么做？
Put that in a separate deposit for headquarters.
用杂项科目存入总部
-And go get it stamped. -Okay.
-然后去拿单据 -好
She's nothing like the Branch Manager described her.
一点也不像分行长说的那样
What are you doing? Hurry up!
你在做什么？快一点
Yes.
是
Go deposit this.
去把钱存入
We're sorry for the wait. It'll only be five more minutes.
抱歉让您久等 再有五分钟就好了
Please wait just a while.
请再稍等一下
-Hurry up. -Of course.
-快点 -是
Hey, you!
喂！
What are you doing?
你在做什么？
Stop doing unnecessary things!
请你不要多事
I'm very sorry.
非常抱歉
It was very busy so…
我看大家手忙脚乱 忍不住就…
Is it a branch inspector's job to work as a teller?
稽查人员也要做柜员的工作吗？
Not at all.
不是这样的
She overstepped her boundary. We apologize.
做了多余的事 真的很抱歉
There is something that caught my attention.
我注意到一件事
Hanasaki.
花琦？
Ms. Nakajima is an excellent bank teller.
中岛小姐是一位优秀的柜员
In fact, everyone except Ms. Nakajima is inexperienced.
但是其他年轻同事
Their level of performance is clearly…
她们的工作能力很明显…
What are you saying?
你想说什么？
Breathe, Hanasaki.
花琦 吸气
Would Ms. Nakajima
中岛小姐真的会犯下
really make such simple mistakes?
那么低级的业务疏忽吗？
I find that hard to believe.
我不这么认为
What?
什么？
Shut up.
你不要说话
Our branch has a detailed business manual.
我们分行有很详尽的工作说明书
With that in hand, anyone can do the work of a teller.
有了那个 谁都能做好柜员的工作
There are things not included
不 并不能完全靠说明书
in the manual that requires teaching by someone.
有些事情只能依赖
Everyone was relying on Ms. Nakajima.
大家都很依赖中岛小姐
There's a lack of experienced tellers in this branch.
这间分行缺乏资深的柜员
Experience is nothing but a number of years.
年资只是数字而已
It doesn't increase their work level.
不代表工作能力有多强
It just means extra expense.
只是徒增人事成本而已
With all due respect…
恕我直言
are female clerks just an expense to you?
女职员对您而言只是人事支出吗？
Of course.
当然了
You are too.
你也是
And I am too.
我也是
Someone who has no knowledge of branch management
你们稽查班的人不懂分行经营状况
has no right to criticize the way we do things.
没资格对我们说三道四
That damn manager gets me so mad!
气死我了 可恶的分行长！
-Watch it. He's the Branch Manager. -So what?
-别说得太过分 他好歹是分行长 -谁叫他说那种话？
"Anyone can become a bank teller"?
“谁都能做好柜员的工作”？
-Stop looking down on the female tellers! -Lower your voice.
-别瞧不起银行女柜员了 -你太大声了
By the way, why are we standing in line for lunch?
为什么我们在排队吃午餐？
The tempura here is…
这里的天妇罗…
-Delicious. -So good!
-好好吃
We finally agree on something.
我们终于有共识了
It's my first time eating such
这么好吃的荞麦面
delicious soba.
我是第一次吃到
We have to visit all the branches
只要是上面交办的
we're assigned to nationwide,
全国各地的分行我们都得去
but the perks of this job are that we can enjoy
好处就是能到各地
local specialties like this.
吃各式各样的美食
Crab in Hokkaido would be nice.
北海道的螃蟹很美味呢
If you want crab, it's Kanazawa.
要吃螃蟹得去金泽
Wait, Fukui is good too.
不 福井的也很好吃
Sounds delicious.
听起来好好吃
There's a place close to here that has delicious deep-fried mackerel,
附近有一家炸竹荚鱼很好吃
and a place with exquisite hashed beef rice.
还有卖美味牛肉烩饭的店
In that case,
这样的话
let's come back.
我们明天也来吧？
I just can't believe that Ms. Nakajima
我还是不相信中岛小姐
made those mistakes.
会犯那些疏漏
And there's something weird about that manager.
而且分行长一定也有问题
No, our job is already done.
不 我们的任务已经结束了
So don't say anything more.
所以别再多嘴了
And don't do anything either.
也不要多事
Why do you look so dissatisfied?
你干嘛一脸不满的样子？
It's nothing.
没事
-Good work. -Thank you.
-拜托你了 -我先离开了
Nakajima.
中岛
How long do you plan to stay here?
你还打算在这里待多久？
There are many people who can replace you.
能取代你的人多的是
Make way for the young ones.
快点把位子让给年轻人吧
Ms. Nakajima.
中岛小姐
Hello.
你好
It seems like everyone was close.
大家看起来感情很好呢
Did all these people transfer to a different branch?
其他人都转调去其他分行了吗？
No, they all quit.
不 她们都离职了
That's why you were the only one helping everyone else.
难怪只有你一个人在支援后辈
I was a teller too,
我以前也是柜员
so I understand your struggle.
所以很明白中岛小姐的辛苦
Ms. Hanasaki, you must have been
花琦小姐
an excellent teller.
一定是一位优秀的柜员
I wouldn't say that I was excellent.
也没那么优秀啦
Thanks for helping.
刚才谢谢你
No problem.
不用谢
Tellers, hurry up!
大家动作快一点
-It's balanced. -Okay.
-结帐明细 -好
-Let's get going.
-差不多该走了 -是
-Nakajima, the spreadsheet. -Is something the matter?
-中岛 表格呢？ -怎么了吗？
-Oh, um… -The cash is unbalanced.
-没事 -现金数字少了
-By how much? -Not much…
-差多少？ -这没什么
One million yen.
一百万元
NOT BALANCED
（金额不符）
Oh… um… this is…
不…
Hanasaki?
花琦？
What are you doing?
你在做什么？
Someone once threw away an envelope of cash
我在中野分行时 有人曾把
at the Nakano Branch.
装现金的纸袋丢掉
Where is the garbage collected?
垃圾场在哪里？
I'll go get it.
我去找
Count it carefully.
仔细地数
-Please count. -Yes.
-麻烦你了 -是
Missing one million yen is unprecedented.
-发生什么事了？ -居然会少一百万元
I'm very sorry.
非常抱歉
Are you trying to ruin our branch?
你打算弄垮这间分行吗？
How was it?
有找到吗？
Manager, what should we do?
分行长 该怎么办？
-We will inspect everyone's belongings. -What?
-检查职员的个人物品 -什么？
You suspect your employees?
你在怀疑自己的员工吗？
Everything at a bank needs to be balanced
在这间银行少一元都不行
down to a yen, but we're dealing with one million yen!
更何况是一百万这么大的数字
We must find it no matter what.
不管怎样都得找到
-But… -I'm very sorry.
-但是… -非常抱歉
It's my fault.
是我的错
-Mr. Yoshida. -Yes.
-吉田课长 -是
-Everyone, your belongings please-- -Excuse me, may I have a word?
-大家把个人物品… -抱歉 我可以说一句话吗？
Let's start by checking the withdrawal slips.
我们可以先检查提款单
There's a chance of overpayment.
也许不小心多给客人了？
What do you say?
您觉得如何呢？
Yeah… let's start by checking the withdrawal slips.
也对 那我们先检查提款单
-Check the withdrawal slips. -Yes.
-检查提款单 -是
-This… -Yeah?
-这个… -嗯？
What did you find?
你找到什么了？
This is a withdrawal slip of 2.5 million yen.
一家叫“黄色芯片”的公司
-To a company called Yellow Chip. -What about it?
-来取250万 -怎么了吗？
Of the 2.5 million yen, he requested
他指定其中的六十万
600,000 in 1,000-yen bills and coins.
要千元钞跟硬币
That means the rest of the 1.9 million was paid with 10,000-yen bills.
剩下的190万是万元钞
1.9 million yen would equal
万元钞票一沓是一百万
one bundle of one million yen.
应该要支付给客人一沓才对
But look here. It says two on here.
但是这里着写两沓
Which means two bundles of 10,000-yen bills were taken.
表示有两沓共两百万的钞票被取出
3.5 million yen was given
这张250万的提款单
for a 2.5 million yen withdrawal.
实际上给出了350万元
-Yes. -Let me see.
-是的 -让我看看
-It's an overpayment. -Unbelievable.
-果然是多给了 -居然有这种事
How did this happen?
怎么会发生这种事？
Mr. Yoshida, didn't you check and confirm it?
吉田课长 你没有确认吗？
What? Uh… well…
什么？这个嘛…
-There is no confirmation stamp. -What?
上面没有你的印章
Explain yourself.
这是怎么回事？
He stepped away from his desk, so I proceeded with the withdrawal.
课长离开座位 所以我就直接处理了
Large withdrawals require
处理大额款项的时候
a second confirmation!
必须再三确认
First a mistake, and now a violation of procedure?
先是业务疏忽 现在又违反流程
I'm very sorry.
真的非常抱歉
Who came in?
是谁来提款的？
President Mikami.
是三上社长
Call him and have him return the money!
还愣在那干嘛？ 快去联系他取回一百万
Yes!
是
YELLOW CHIP INC.
（黄色芯片股份有限公司）
Good evening.
承蒙贵公司长期惠顾
I'm the Deputy General Manager Yoshida from Tokyo Daiichi Bank Kayabacho Branch.
我是东京第一银行 茅场町分行营业课长吉田
300,000 yen in 1,000-yen bills.
给我三十万的千元钞
And another 300,000 yen in…
另外三十万…
Hello, President Mikami.
三上社长
Thank you for coming in today.
感谢您今日光临敝分行
I'm very sorry to bother you with this,
很抱歉打扰您
but we made an error
我们今天犯了一个错误
and handed you more than the specified amount.
不小心给您多于提款金额的现金了
Oh… what… but…
什么？但是…
well…
这…
I understand. We will check it over once more.
我了解了 我们会再次进行确认
Good bye.
再见
He says that he didn't receive extra.
他说他没有多拿现金
Stop that nonsense. How can that be?
别乱说了 怎么可能？
What idiot would accept that as an answer?
你怎么会相信这种说法？
-It's one million yen! -I… I'm very sorry.
-那可是一百万元 -非常抱歉
What kind of a company is Yellow Chip?
这家黄色芯片是怎么样的公司呢？
It's a small company that's been with us for few years.
是小型公司 三年前开始跟我们合作
And their business?
他们的业绩如何？
They used to be doing well.
以前还不错
But lately, they've been in a deficit.
但最近开始亏损
There's no doubt about it.
一定是这样
Their business isn't doing well,
他们的营运状况不佳
and they unexpectedly received an extra one million yen.
意外多拿到一百万
They're trying to keep that money.
打算私吞这笔钱
Even though it's our error…
但这仍然是我们的疏忽
-Hey! -Yes?
-喂 -是
-Isn't there anything you can do? -Well…
-你们不打算做点什么吗？ -就算您这样说…
Um…
那个…
Why don't we check the security footage?
要不要检查监视器画面？
-It's hard to see. Can't you zoom in? -Yes.
看不太清楚 可以放大吗？
If the correct amount was given, there should be
-是 -正常的情况下
three bundles of 1,000-yen bills and one bundle of 10,000-yen bills.
应该会有三沓千元钞和一沓万元钞
So there should be four bundles.
总共四沓纸钞
There's five.
有五沓
I see five bundles.
她给了五沓纸钞
That president lied to us!
那个社长在说谎
Kawamoto and Yoshida, go get it back.
河本、吉田 你们去把钱拿回来
Yes!
-是
How will you pay for this?
你打算怎么弥补？
An accident with one million in cash will affect
这么大金额的疏漏 不只你会有问题
the performance of this branch!
整个分行都会被拖累
We pay you good money, and yet you're causing us trouble.
给你这么高的薪水 你却不断制造问题
You're losing us money!
真划不来 这是很大的损失
-That's not-- -Shut up, outsider.
-这样说也太… -外人不要多嘴
I'm sorry.
非常抱歉
-Sorry we're late. -How was it?
-抱歉这么晚回来 -顺利吗？
Well…
这个嘛…
President Mikami insists that he didn't receive extra.
三上社长坚持说他没有多拿钱
-What… -That can't be!
-怎么会… -真没用
So you just came back?
你们就这样空手而回？
I'm very sorry.
-非常抱歉
Isn't there anything we can do?
我们什么忙都帮不上吗？
You already know that
你也很清楚
once cash is handed over, no one can question the amount
交易结束之后 就不能质疑
that was paid out.
已经付出的金额
"Cash leaves no trail." That's the principle.
现金交易后就无法追讨 这是规矩
-Kawamoto. -Yes.
-河本 -是
Poor Ms. Nakajima.
中岛小姐好可怜
The Branch Manager is going to do something again…
发生这种事 一定又会被分行长骂
Excuse me…
不好意思
What do you mean by "again"?
你说“又”是什么意思？
Is Ms. Nakajima
难道分行长
being treated badly by the Branch Manager?
之前也对中岛小姐很不好吗？
Yes.
是的
Branch Manager is very harsh towards Ms. Nakajima.
分行长对中岛小姐非常严厉
He yells at her in front of everyone.
他会在大家面前对她大吼
He blames her
我们犯了错
for all of our mistakes.
也都是中岛小姐遭殃
Does that mean she's forced to take responsibility
意思是说中岛小姐承担了
for mistakes she didn't make?
不是她造成的过错吗？
Yes.
是的
Everyone can go home now.
大家今天可以下班了
We got an appointment with Mr. Mikami.
我们跟三上社长约好要见面
I'll go and have a talk with him.
我会直接去找他谈
-Thank you very much. -Sure.
-麻烦您了 -嗯
-Good bye.
-您慢走
What happens if we can't get that money back?
如果拿不回这笔钱会怎样呢？
I've never heard of one million yen missing in cash.
我之前也没碰过弄丢一百万元的事
Both Ms. Nakajima and Branch Manager
中岛小姐
will have to take responsibility for this.
和矢岛分行长都必须为此事负责
You're right…
是啊
But I'm sure he'll get it back no matter what.
但他一定会用尽方法把钱拿回来
One mistake will put an X-mark on your career, and everything will be over.
就算只失误过一次 一旦留下污点 就完蛋了
That's banks.
这就是银行
RESTAURANT HANASAKI
（花琦食堂）
I wonder if she'll get fired.
不知道她会不会被解雇？
What? You're getting fired?
什么？你要被炒鱿鱼了？
This isn't about me.
不是我啦
It's about a teller I met at a branch office.
是我们去稽查的分行职员
What did that person do?
她做了什么事？
I can't tell you that.
我不能告诉你
What?
什么嘛
But it's typical of you to worry about someone
但是关心初次见面的陌生人
you only met today.
果然像你会做的事
Because she's a teller, and we work at the same bank.
毕竟她是同一家银行的柜员前辈
And apparently, the Branch Manager is very capable,
而且那个分行长虽然很能干的样子
but he's a horrible person, and he's so annoying.
但人品很差 让人生气
Your tendency to worry about people,
你总是为别人担心
is just like your late mother.
这一点跟你过世的妈妈还真像
I'm not as meddlesome as Mom.
我才不像妈妈那么多事
I see no difference.
你们俩不相上下
It's a call for a reservation.
是预约的电话
Hello, this is Hanasaki.
花琦食堂 你好
I hope they can retrieve the million yen.
希望他们能把一百万拿回来
You got it back?
拿回一百万元了？
-Count it. -Yes.
-数数看 -是
I was sincere and persistent, so he gave it back to me.
看我这么诚心又不放弃 他就把钱还回了
I guess Mr. Mikami felt a pang of remorse.
三上社长应该也感到良心不安吧？
-I see. -I'm so glad.
-原来如此 -太好了
You're amazing.
不愧是分行长
It's one million yen.
是一百万元没错
We finally got back the million yen.
终于把一百万元拿回来了
This is great news, Ms. Nakajima.
中岛小姐 太好了
Yeah.
是啊
I apologize for causing such trouble.
抱歉造成这么大的骚动
-Not at all. -I have a request to make.
-不会 -我想跟你商量一件事
Can you please overlook
这次的事件
this issue with the overpayment?
你们可以当作不知情吗？
Are you telling me not to report it to headquarters?
你希望我们不要向上汇报吗？
We will provide strict guidance
我们会严厉监督
so that this will never happen again.
不会再让这种事发生 拜托了
I understand.
我了解了
-Let's go back to headquarters. -Yes.
-我们回总部吧 -是
Ms. Nakajima, I'm glad it all worked out.
中岛小姐 真是太好了
Yes.
嗯
What? Did Mr. Soma
相马先生呢？
leave without me?
自己先走了？
-I'm so sorry. -It's my fault.
-抱歉 -不 是我不好
-Are you okay? -Yes.
-你没事吧？ -没事
YELLOW CHIP INC.
（黄色芯片股份有限公司）
-Oh! -What?
-哎呀 -怎么了？
By any chance,
不好意思
are you Mr. Mikami?
请问您是三上先生吗？
Yes.
是的
I'm Hanasaki from the headquarters of Tokyo Daiichi Bank.
我是东京第一银行总部的花琦
I'm very sorry
因为我们昨日的疏忽
for causing you much trouble
造成您的不便
due to an error on our part.
真的非常抱歉
Um…
那个…
I came to close my account.
我是来结清帐户的
I don't want my bank to be treating me like a robber.
我不想和把我当作小偷的银行来往
I'm sorry if they have offended you.
很抱歉 让您碰到这种事
The Branch Manager here is terrible.
这间分行的行长很过分
Yes! I mean…
对 我是说
He blamed me for stealing a million yen,
他擅自认定我拿走一百万
so I denied it, but he wouldn't back down.
我已经否认了 他还坚持是我的错
I couldn't take it anymore,
我实在受不了
so I said that I'd call the police.
就问他要不要报警处理
Then he finally shut up and left.
他才闭嘴离开
-Shut up and left? -Yes.
-闭嘴离开？ -对
So, did you end up finding the money?
你们最后找到钱了吗？
The money?
钱？
The one million yen.
就是那一百万元
You overpaid it somewhere, right?
你们不小心多给客户了吧？
That's what the Branch Manager said.
你们分行长是这样说的
What? Didn't you return the million yen…
三上社长没有还回一百万吗？
What?
什么？
-There was no overpayment? -Yes, Mr. Mikami never received it.
-根本没有多给钱？ -对 三上社长一开始
He didn't get that extra million yen!
就没有多拿钱
-I'm sure of it! -But the manager.
-我非常确定 -但是分行长
He said that he got back the million yen.
不是说他把一百万拿回来了吗？
Plus, the security footage showed that he was overpaid.
而且监视画面也都拍到了
But I don't think Mr. Mikami was lying.
是这样没错
Mr. Soma.
相马先生
-I'm going to check that video again. -What?
-我要再去确认一次监视画面 -什么？
I might find something.
说不定可以发现什么
-I'll be off. -Wait! Hanasaki!
-我出发了 -等一下 花琦！
-Ouch. -Sorry.
-哎呀！ -抱歉
-Bye. -Where's she going?
-我出发了 -她要去哪里？
Something feels off…
总觉得哪里怪怪的
Hm?
嗯？
Don't tell me…
这该不会是…
Thank you very much.
抱歉让您久等了
Ms. Nakajima.
中岛小姐
There was never an overpayment to begin with.
你一开始就没有多给钱
I went through yesterday's security footage again.
昨天的监视画面我又看了一遍
It was very busy when
三上社长来的时候
Mr. Mikami came into the bank.
银行非常忙碌
Ms. Nakajima, you offered an apology
中岛小姐通常都会对客人说
and gave a packet of tissues
“抱歉久等了”
to all the customers that had to wait.
同时给对方一包面纸 对吗？
Yes.
对
But for some reason, you didn't give tissues
但是你却没有给
to Mr. Mikami.
三上社长
Even though you gave them to everyone else.
其他的客人你都有给
That got me curious,
我有点在意这件事
so I checked again.
于是再次确认画面
At first glance, it looks like there are five bundles of bills.
第一眼的确会以为是五沓钞票
But one of them
但其实其中一沓
is not a bundle of bills.
不是钞票
It's a packet of tissue, isn't it?
而是面纸 对吧？
You took out 3.5 million yen,
客人要领取250万
for the 2.5 million withdrawal request.
于是你领出350万元现金
Then you took out one million yen
然后把一百万元拿走
and handed 2.5 million yen to Mr. Mikami
再将250万的现金附上面纸
together with a packet of tissues.
一起交给三上社长
You only gave Mr. Mikami four bundles of bills.
你只给三上社长四沓纸钞
He was not overpaid.
也就是说他没有多拿钱
You took
你把一百万
the one million yen, right?
拿走了 对吧？
Yes.
对
Why?
为什么？
This is illegal. Why did you do it?
这是犯罪 为什么要做这种事？
You betrayed
你背叛了
everyone that you work with.
所有的同事
I…
我…
love being a bank teller.
喜欢柜员的工作
You're only with the customer for a short while,
招呼客人的时间虽然短暂
but they share all sorts of
但客人会和我聊
personal and family
家人、考试
events with you, such as
入学、就职
entrance exams, school admission,
结婚生子
employment, marriage and childbirth.
各种生活大小事
It made me so happy
听到客人跟我说谢谢时
when they said, "Thank you."
我都会很开心
Every day was a challenge,
每天都很辛苦
but it was fun.
但是也很开心
Is it not the same for you?
中岛小姐不是这样吗？
Ms. Nakajima!
中岛小姐！
I like being a teller too.
我也喜欢柜员的工作
-Then why did you-- -I wanted to put an X-mark on him.
-那你为什么… -我想要在分行长的职涯
On the manager's career.
留下一个污点
Is that…
这是…
The manager would have to take responsibility
如果真的弄丢一百万现金
for an incident concerning one million yen.
分行长一定得负责吧？
Was it to take revenge for his
这是为了报复分行长
harassment?
对你的职场骚扰吗？
-But-- -I couldn't forgive him!
-但是… -我就是无法原谅
About those three that quit.
那三个人离职的事
Three people?
三个人？
It seems like everyone is close.
大家看起来感情很好呢
Were those three employees
该不会那三个离职的人
treated badly by the manager too?
也被分行长骚扰？
No matter how hard
无论我们这些女职员
the female employees worked, the Branch Manager only saw us
多努力工作 对分行长来说
as an unnecessary expense.
只是浪费公司钱的麻烦职员
That's unacceptable.
这也太不合理了
You should've reported that!
为什么没有向人事部反映呢？
But I know that it's useless to do that.
就算反映了也无济于事
I would have been silenced if I complained about the harassment.
反映职权骚扰的人只会被漠视
If you went to the higher--
如果你向更上层报告…
Who do you think will listen to us?
你觉得谁会听我们说的话呢？
Who can make the manager take responsibility?
谁会让分行长负起责任呢？
There's no one who can do that!
根本就没有这种人
In the end,
最后
I even dragged Mr. Mikami into it,
我还把三上社长拖下水
but
没想到
the overpayment won't even be reported.
这个问题根本不会被汇报
What?
什么？
Then where did the Branch Manager get the million yen?
那今天分行长拿来的一百万元是…
-He compensated it himself. -No way.
-他拿自己的钱补贴的 -怎么可能？
He only thinks of being promoted, so I wouldn't
分行长一心只想要升迁
put it past him.
所以才这样做
Basically,
到头来
nothing will change even if I
就算我起身反抗
fight back.
也没能改变什么
Today I will
今天
return the money and apologize.
我会归还一百万 并且道歉
I'm ready to accept all responsibility.
我已经准备好承担后果
Are you serious?
你说的是真的吗？
If that's true, it's a big deal.
这是非常严重的事
But do you think the Branch Manager compensated
但你真的认为分行长
the million yen?
会自掏腰包赔钱吗？
That's unacceptable as a bank employee.
银行职员是绝对不能这样做的
He probably attempted to cover it up
但他为了不让自己的职涯留下污点
in order to prevent ruining his career.
所以打算隐瞒这件事 也很合理吧？
But we have no proof.
但我们没有证据
Hello? Hanasaki?
喂？花琦？
Mr. Soma, there's something I want you to look into.
相马先生 我有一件事想要调查
What is it?
什么事？
The three tellers who resigned from Kayabacho.
从茅场町分行离职的那三名柜员
What?
什么？
TOKYO DAIICHI BANK
（东京第一银行）
I won't forgive him.
我绝不会原谅他
It's all balanced.
3点12分 结帐完成
Thank you for your hard work.
今天也辛苦大家了
Thank you.
辛苦了
-What is that? -One million yen.
-这是什么？ -一百万元
I took it.
是我拿走的
-What? -I'm very sorry.
-什么？ -真的非常抱歉
Ms. Nakajima took it?
是中岛小姐拿走的？
That's horrible.
好过分
Please explain yourself.
到底是怎么一回事？
Did you try to steal this money?
你假装多付给客人 打算私吞这笔钱？
-Is that right? -What have you done?
-是这样吗？ -你到底做了什么？
Do you have something against me?
你对我有什么不满吗？
What do you think will happen
你没想过事情爆发后
when this gets out?
会有什么下场吗？
Are you trying to ruin my life?
你打算毁了我的人生吗？
Say something!
你倒是说话啊！
Hey!
喂！
Nakajima, say something!
中岛 你说话啊！
Answer me, Nakajima!
中岛 回答我！
Mr. Yajima!
矢岛分行长！
What are you doing here?
你在这干嘛？
Leave, this doesn't concern you.
不相关的外人请离开
You don't know why Ms. Nakajima
你知道为什么中岛小姐
did this?
要做这种事吗？
What? How would I know?
我怎么会知道？
It's for revenge.
是为了报复你
Ridiculous.
说什么蠢话？
Since you came here a year ago,
分行长一年前来到这里后
Ms. Sachiko Tanaka,
田中幸子
Ms. Kaori Ishii, and Ms. Kiyomi Fujiwara
石井香织、藤原清
have resigned.
共三名女职员离职
What they all have in common is that
这三人有共同点
they're all experienced clerks with level one rank.
她们都是事务职一级的柜员
LEVEL ONE RANK CLERK
（事务职一级）
Level one clerks have high qualifications,
事务职一级代表工作能力优秀
and high salaries.
薪水也较高
Without them, paperwork becomes stagnant, and errors increase.
她们辞职的话 会让行政疏漏增加
But you decided to prioritize
但是分行长却为了让业绩上升
this branch's sales increase,
让她们离职
by cutting costs.
以减少支出
That's why you made them quit,
是你不断地骚扰她们
by harassing them.
才逼她们离职的
Stop this false accusation.
你根本胡说八道
All of these women resigned voluntarily.
她们全都是自愿离职的
No, it was not voluntary.
不 她们不是自愿的
Everyone said, "Branch Manager Yajima
每个人都说是被矢岛分行长
made me quit."
逼迫离职的
I met and talked with all three of the former employees.
我已经和她们三位见过面了
Ms. Tanaka, who had the most years of experience,
最资深的田中小姐
was the first target,
是最初被针对的职员
and she was offered a transfer.
最后被恶意调职
-You've been transferred. -What?
-你要被调职了 -什么？
For Ms. Tanaka who has a young child,
因为田中小姐有年幼的孩子
transferring was not an option, so she had no choice but to quit.
她无法调职 只好选择离职
I tried to take maternity leave…
其实我有想过要请产假
As for Ms. Ishii's maternity leave…
石井曾向公司请产假
Don't you know how busy we are?
你知道公司现在多忙吗？
She was told "This is why women are a hassle. You cause extra burdens.
她被你说“女人一点用都没有 只会添麻烦
Your position won't be open when you come back." So she quit.
这里不会有你的位子” 之后就离职了
I have a chronic kidney disease…
我有肾脏疾病
Ms. Fujiwara, who has a chronic illness,
藤原小姐患有慢性疾病
was using her paid leave to visit the hospital,
她请病假去看医生
but she was accused of taking many days off.
却被指责请太多假
She was unable to cope with
她承受不住精神压力
the emotional pressure, so she quit.
最后选择离职
Everyone said…
每个人都说
"I wanted to continue working here.
在矢岛分行长来这之前
I liked this workplace.
本来打算继续工作
Until Mr. Yajima came here."
也喜欢在这里工作
That's absurd.
真是荒唐
They're saying that out of spite.
她们只是想陷害我
Listen, what Ms. Nakajima did was embezzlement.
听好了 中岛可是打算侵占客人财产
Of course, what Ms. Nakajima did is unforgivable.
中岛小姐的行为当然是不对的
But she chose this as a last resort, in order to place
但她是因为想在你的职涯留下污点
an X-mark on your career.
才选择终极手段
By risking her own.
不惜牺牲自己的人生
-He really did that? -How horrible.
-他真的做了那些事？ -真是过分
Are you saying that it's wrong to
我想让分行业绩上升
increase the sales of a branch office?
有什么不对吗？
Cutting off personnel who are not worthy of the expense,
让能力与薪资不符的职员走人
is for the bank!
都是为公司着想
With all due respect…
恕我直言
is it really for the bank?
这真的是为银行着想吗？
Isn't it for your own promotion?
难道不是为了自己的升迁吗？
I don't know much about branch management.
我不清楚分行的经营状况
But it's wrong to bully female clerks
但是为了降低成本
in order to make them quit and cut costs.
欺负女职员逼她们离职 一点也不合理
-Shut up. -No, I will not!
-闭嘴 -我不要！
You just asked
分行长刚才说
"are you trying to ruin my life?" but
“你打算毁了我的人生吗？”
the same can be said for these female clerks and Ms. Nakajima.
你也毁了中岛小姐和其他人的人生
All of them
她们每个人
have lives that they need to protect!
也都尽力在守护自己的人生
Just because you're a boss,
不能因为你是上司
doesn't give you the right to ruin their lives.
就肆意破坏部下的人生
Shut up.
吵死了
What would you know?
你又懂什么了？
As a banker,
我身为银行家
I haven't done anything wrong.
完全没有做错事
Um, may I have a minute?
抱歉 我可以说几句吗？
Mr. Soma.
相马先生
Excuse me.
不好意思
This is a copy of Mr. Yajima
这是矢岛分行长
and Mr. Kawamoto's accounts.
和河本次长的存折影本
I'm sorry for taking the liberty to do so, but I noticed
抱歉擅自做了这件事 但是今早
that both of you
你们两个
withdrew money from the same ATM this morning.
都从同一个提款机提款
Mr. Yajima withdrew 700,000
矢岛分行长提领七十万
and Mr. Kawamoto withdrew…
河本次长提领
-300,000. -Oh…
三十万
That adds up to one million yen.
加起来总共一百万
It's the same amount as
这和不小心多给客人
the one million yen you said you retrieved back
并已取回的一百万元
from the customer that was overpaid.
完全符合
Is this a coincidence?
这只是巧合吗？
Did you both compensate this money,
两位是不是为了隐瞒本次的事件
in order to cover up the incident at this branch?
用自己的钱补贴损失呢？
When I became a bank teller,
我还是柜员的时候
this is what I was taught.
是这样被教导的
When the numbers do not add up, an employee must never compensate it,
金额对不上的时候 就算只差一元
even if it's only one yen.
也绝对不能自己补贴
Branch Manager,
分行长
will you still claim that you've done nothing wrong?
这样您还自称什么过错都没有吗？
You always do as you please.
真是的 每次都擅自行动
I'm sorry.
对不起
But you did too, Mr. Soma.
但是你也一样
What?
什么？
You checked Mr. Yajima's bank account, right?
你擅自调查了分行长的存折吧？
Thank you.
谢谢你
I don't need you to thank me.
我不需要你和我道谢
Um…
那个…
Ms. Nakajima.
中岛小姐
Ms. Hanasaki.
花琦小姐
-Thank you. -It was nothing.
-谢谢你 -没什么
No one has ever spoken to the Branch Manager like that
从来没人敢那样对分行长说话
until now.
你是第一个
Thank you for defending those three employees too.
也谢谢你帮那三位离职的人说话
Ms. Nakajima,
中岛小姐
I was bitter because I had to leave
我从柜员
the job I liked as a teller and become a dreaded
被调到讨人厌的稽查班时
branch inspector.
老实说感觉很痛苦
Being a branch inspector opened my eyes to things I never knew before.
开始临店稽查的工作后 看到了很多
Like the stuffy, old-fashioned side of banking,
银行守旧又僵化的处理方式
and the tension caused by
派系、组织、升迁
factions, organizations, and promotions.
这类的陋习层出不穷
That's all I see.
全都是这种事
It's horrible.
真的很糟糕
But
但是
I'm going to give it my all.
我会努力的
I'll work at this job the best I can.
我会尽力做好这份工作
I think you'll be able to change,
我相信你一定能改变
the stuffy, old-fashioned bank.
守旧又僵化的银行
Good luck.
加油
Yes.
是
Who would have thought that such a big problem would arise during inspection.
没想到分行那边出了这么大的事
They were able to solve the issue.
他们已经协助处理
It should be fine.
应该没问题了
But the Branch Manager from the Shindo faction
但是那个分行长是真藤派的
had to be transferred.
被调职了
Will everything be all right?
这样不会有事吗？
I think so.
这样也不错啊
PERSONNEL NOTICE
（人事调动）
SHUNZO YAJIMA - CURRENT POST - MANAGER TOKYO DAIICHI BANK KAYABACHO BRANCH
（现任茅场町分行长 矢岛俊三）
NEW POST - TOKYO FIRST ELECTRIC INC.
（调派至东京第一电工）
Yajima was transferred to First Electric?
矢岛被调到第一电工？
Y… yes.
是
This transfer is
这个调动是
a one-way ticket with no chance of return.
单向的 没有机会再回来了
What do you mean?
怎么回事？
They couldn't cover up some minor scandal?
他们没办法掩盖这种小丑闻？
Well…
这个…
it seems like the branch inspectors did something unnecessary.
看来是稽查班的人多管闲事了
-Inspectors? -Yes.
-稽查班？ -对
They brought Yajima down?
矢岛居然是被他们害的
How dare they mess around like this.
稽查班居然敢这样乱来
-Good morning. -Morning.
-早安
Hey, what happened to everything that was on this desk?
本来在桌上的东西去哪了？
I put it together over there.
我放到那里了
This is my desk,
这是我的座位
so please keep things within your space.
请把东西收在自己的位子
Oh, and it seems like
中岛小姐好像
Ms. Nakajima is looking for a new job. I'm glad.
在找新工作了 太好了
Don't get ahead of yourself.
别得意忘形了
Things just happened to work out this time.
这次只是刚好没事而已
-You think so? -Of course!
-是这样吗？ -那当然
-The troubles at the branch-- -Listen.
-分行的问题… -听好
Don't say a single unnecessary thing at future inspections.
之后临店稽查 一律不要多嘴
It wasn't unnecessary.
我那不是多嘴
-Yes, it was. -No, it wasn't.
-就是 -不是
I don't want to be dragged into things.
我不想被卷入麻烦
-With all due respect… -Shut up.
-恕我直言… -闭嘴
No, I will not!
我不要！
This is fraud!
这算是诈欺吧？
That means our bank was lending a hand to fraud.
我们银行把钱贷给了诈欺公司
50 million will be unrecoverable.
我们贷出的五千万可能无法回收
It's your fault!
一切都是你的责任！
What's going on?
现在是什么情况？
-Wait! -There's always trouble
-等一下！ -那两个稽查人员
wherever they go.
到哪都会出问题
Kiss my ass!
都去吃屎吧！
Subtitle translation by: Lili Morita
字幕翻译：李瑜